<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nothing without God. Courteous reader, after my travels the Lord hath been pleased to bring me safe to this former place of my habitation ...</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B27494</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888681</idno>
  <idno type="VID">195889</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240903428</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing N1395A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.112.f.9[84]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R231535</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888681</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99888681e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B27494)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 195889)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; E8:1[85])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Nothing without God. Courteous reader, after my travels the Lord hath been pleased to bring me safe to this former place of my habitation ...</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1670?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint information from Wing.</note>
                  <note>At end of text: Soli Deo Gloria.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Advertising --  Medicine --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Medicine --  Formulae, receipts, prescriptions --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Physicians --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="advert_for_medicines">
            <pb facs="tcp:195889:1"/>
            <head>Nothing without God.</head>
            <p>COurteous Reader, after my Travels the Lord hath been pleased to bring me safe to this former Place of my Habitation; He hath also been good unto me to Answer me in that I have Sought after, and as he hath given to me ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny large Talents, I desire with the assistance of him to put them forth to the best use for the good of the World, that when my Lord cometh to inquire of me what use I have made, he may find them doubled, and then will he say, <hi>Well done Good and Faithfull Servant.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I have by my Study and Travel, with the Blessing of God on my Endeavours, found out many rare secrets in Physick, and performed many rare Cures to the ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miration of those that knew the Patients Sick, and after see them recovered; I shall only name some particulars, which are these following.
<list>
                  <item>A perfect Cure for Consumptions, Coughs, and all other Diseases of the Lungs, Rickets in Children, Gravel, the Stone, Pains of the Spleen, Dropsies, Jaundies both Black and Yellow, Agues, Feavers, Palsies; I have a per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect Cure for any that are Distracted.</item>
                  <item>I seldom or never fail the Cure of Convulsion Fits, Falling Sickness, Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Fits, Pains of the Head, Back, or Stomach, Pains or Lameness of the Limbs, also Pains of the Teeth, Rup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, also Wens, Cancers in the Breast, Cankers, Ulcers, Fistulaes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>These, with many other Diseases, are by the Blessing of God by me Cured: If any be Diseased, Let them repair to me, or send their Urine, and I shall be free in my Advice or Direction to all, for the Lord hath Called, and I must Hear. <hi>When the Poor Cry, shall I stop my Ears? No, God forbid, the Poor of the world are Rich in God</hi> I will not be like the Physitians of the times, Look into the 5th. <hi>chap.</hi> of <hi>Jeremiah vers.</hi> 28. that agrees with them. If any of the World be trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled or offended at my good will to all, Let me satisfie them with the wise Savings of <hi>Solomon, Prov.</hi> 3. <hi>vers.</hi> 32. <hi>For the froward is abomination to the Lord, but his Secrets is with the Righteous.</hi> As the Lord hath given me a healing Hand, I am willing to Imploy it with Thankfulness,</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Farewell.</salute>
            </closer>
            <closer>Soli Deo Gloria,</closer>
            <argument>
               <p>I Live in <hi>Little Trinity-lane</hi> near <hi>Queen-Hithe</hi> at Mr. <hi>Gwins</hi> a Cloath-worker <hi>LONDON.</hi>
               </p>
            </argument>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>